const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"A railway master, while traveling, saw a dead body that was cut into equal left and right halves. The body was cut in which anatomical plane?","answers":[{"option":"Right paramedian plane","bool":false},{"option":"Median sagittal plane","bool":true},{"option":"Transverse plane","bool":false},{"option":"Left paramedian plane","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal plane","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What is the action of a drug on the body known as?","answers":[{"option":"Bioavailability","bool":false},{"option":"Solubility","bool":false},{"option":"Pharmacodynamics","bool":true},{"option":"Drug clearance","bool":false},{"option":"Pharmacokinetics","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What type of epithelium is present in the conjunctiva?","answers":[{"option":"Transitional","bool":false},{"option":"Keratinized","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroepithelial","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified columnar","bool":true},{"option":"Simple","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of these is our body unable to synthesize?","answers":[{"option":"Saturated fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Essential fatty acids","bool":true},{"option":"Non-essential fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Unsaturated fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What is the prolonged cumulative sub-lethal injury in a cell known as?","answers":[{"option":"Phagocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Cellular aging","bool":true},{"option":"Apoptosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitosis","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of the following causes protein aggregation?","answers":[{"option":"Endoplasmic reticulum dysfunction","bool":true},{"option":"Ribosomal dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Cell wall dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleic acid dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi dysfunction","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Lipids are formed by the condensation of which substances?","answers":[{"option":"Fatty acids and alcohol","bool":true},{"option":"Fatty acids and amino acid","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon and hydrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty acids and carbohydrate","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty acids and amines","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which one of these is a derived lipid?","answers":[{"option":"Oil","bool":false},{"option":"Steroids","bool":true},{"option":"Paraffin","bool":false},{"option":"Waxes","bool":false},{"option":"Fat","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"How can the therapeutic index be calculated?","answers":[{"option":"Pharmacokinetics/pharmacodynamics","bool":false},{"option":"TD₅₀/ED₅₀","bool":true},{"option":"Efficacy/potency","bool":false},{"option":"PT/INR","bool":false},{"option":"[E]/[Eₘ‎ₐₓ]","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What initiates and controls amoeboid movement?","answers":[{"option":"Phototropism","bool":false},{"option":"Bones","bool":false},{"option":"Chemotaxis","bool":true},{"option":"Engine","bool":false},{"option":"Geotaxis","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which type of joint is present between the epiphysis and diaphysis?","answers":[{"option":"Synchondrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Ball and socket","bool":false},{"option":"Syndesmosis","bool":false},{"option":"Gomphosis","bool":false},{"option":"Suture","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which disease is caused by the failure of cranial neuropore closure?","answers":[{"option":"Spina bifida","bool":false},{"option":"Neural cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Anencephaly","bool":true},{"option":"Gliosis","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"The number of oogonia is maximum at what time in a female's life?","answers":[{"option":"End of 4th month of development","bool":false},{"option":"Beginning of 3rd month of development","bool":false},{"option":"End of 5th month of development","bool":true},{"option":"2nd trimester of pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"At birth","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"When does the pupillary light reflex begin?","answers":[{"option":"After birth","bool":false},{"option":"24th week","bool":false},{"option":"11th week","bool":false},{"option":"30th week","bool":true},{"option":"7th week","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of these is an elastic artery?","answers":[{"option":"Axillary","bool":false},{"option":"Aorta","bool":true},{"option":"Tracheal","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal","bool":false},{"option":"Ulnar","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a phase I reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Reduction","bool":false},{"option":"Oxidation","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Glucuronidation","bool":true},{"option":"Deamination","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which disease is characterized by the immobility of cilia and flagella?","answers":[{"option":"Cystic fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Herler disease","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Immotile cilia syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Pernicious anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Where is type 1 collagen not found?","answers":[{"option":"Basal lamina","bool":true},{"option":"Cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Bone","bool":false},{"option":"Blood vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Cornea","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of these junctions is present in the most apical part, along the lateral plasma membranes, of epithelial cells?","answers":[{"option":"Macula adherens","bool":false},{"option":"Tight junctions","bool":true},{"option":"Zonula adherens","bool":false},{"option":"Gap junctions","bool":false},{"option":"Hemidesmosome","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What are the cells which form myelin sheath on the axons of peripheral nerves derived from?","answers":[{"option":"Neural crest cells","bool":true},{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Yolk sac","bool":false},{"option":"Hematopoietic stem cells","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of these is not a part of a typical spinal nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Ventral root ganglion","bool":true},{"option":"Rootlets","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal root ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior ramus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior ramus","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What is the function of pseudo-unipolar neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Conveys message to pons","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulates effectors","bool":false},{"option":"Conveys message to spinal cord","bool":true},{"option":"Acts as a receptor for external stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What type of glands are sweat glands?","answers":[{"option":"Seromucous glands","bool":false},{"option":"Mammary glands","bool":false},{"option":"Holocrine glands","bool":false},{"option":"Branched acinar glands","bool":false},{"option":"Merocrine glands","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"How can the age of a fetus during the embryonic period be measured accurately?","answers":[{"option":"Last natural menstrual period","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon dating","bool":false},{"option":"Crown-rump length (CRL)","bool":true},{"option":"Biparietal diameter","bool":false},{"option":"Number of somites","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"When fertilization occurs, the corpus luteum continues to produce progesterone for how long?","answers":[{"option":"9 days","bool":false},{"option":"4 months","bool":true},{"option":"21 days","bool":false},{"option":"Till birth","bool":false},{"option":"2 months","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What are the blood vessels in skin supplied by?","answers":[{"option":"Autonomic sympathetic fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Autonomic parasympathetic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic sympathetic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic sensory nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic motor nerves","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which disease does not involve sex chromosomes?","answers":[{"option":"Turner syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Triple X syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Duchenne muscular dystrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Klinefelter Syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer's disease","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a characteristic of apoptosis?","answers":[{"option":"Nuclear condensation","bool":false},{"option":"Membrane blebbing","bool":false},{"option":"Shrinkage","bool":false},{"option":"Cellular fragmentation","bool":false},{"option":"Swelling","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What does a necrotic cell stained with hematoxylin and eosin (H&E) stain show?","answers":[{"option":"Increased eosinophilia","bool":true},{"option":"Increased basophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased basophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased eosinophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Non-glassy structure","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Sertoli cells are derived from which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":true},{"option":"Hematopoietic stem cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sustentacular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sperm cells","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"The diffusion potential of the cell membrane is calculated by the movement of which of the following ions?","answers":[{"option":"Na+","bool":false},{"option":"Several different ions","bool":true},{"option":"K+","bool":false},{"option":"Cl-","bool":false},{"option":"HCO3-","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Growth of hyaline cartilage is controlled by which hormone of anterior pituitary gland?","answers":[{"option":"Gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Thyrotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Somatotropin","bool":true},{"option":"Androgen","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a function of sertoli cells?","answers":[{"option":"Forms germ cells","bool":true},{"option":"Assists in the release of mature spermatozoa","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytosis of residual cytoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Supports germ cells","bool":false},{"option":"Protects germ cells","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of these is a cause of muscle hypertrophy?","answers":[{"option":"Increased work load","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased water intake","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased work load","bool":false},{"option":"Ischemia","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of these is a hallmark of reversible cell injury?","answers":[{"option":"Cell shrinkage","bool":false},{"option":"Apoptotic bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Pyknosis","bool":false},{"option":"Nuclear fragmentation","bool":false},{"option":"Cellular swelling","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"The amniotic cavity is formed within which cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Syncytiotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Epiblast","bool":true},{"option":"Cytotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Amnioblast","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Where is the non-keratinized stratified squamous epithelium not present?","answers":[{"option":"Esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Mouth and tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Nasopharynx and laryngopharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Cornea and conjunctiva","bool":true},{"option":"Anal canal","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of these is not derived from ectoderm?","answers":[{"option":"Meninges","bool":false},{"option":"Central nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Enamel of teeth","bool":false},{"option":"Mammary glands","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of these store information about the epitope of an antigen?","answers":[{"option":"Hematopoetic stem cells","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma B cells","bool":false},{"option":"Helper T cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotoxic T cells","bool":false},{"option":"Memory B cells","bool":true}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"After what time do oogonia stop forming?","answers":[{"option":"Puberty","bool":false},{"option":"5th month of fetal life","bool":true},{"option":"Birth","bool":false},{"option":"1st week of fetal life","bool":false},{"option":"Menopause","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which vessel(s) is/are present in the umbilical cord?","answers":[{"option":"Two veins","bool":false},{"option":"Vitelline vessels","bool":false},{"option":"One artery","bool":false},{"option":"One artery and one vein","bool":false},{"option":"Two arteries and one vein","bool":true}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which protein is found abundantly in the bone matrix?","answers":[{"option":"Keratin","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen type 1","bool":true},{"option":"Osseous protein","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen type 2","bool":false},{"option":"Amylase","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of these is not directly related to pathology?","answers":[{"option":"Polymorphism","bool":true},{"option":"Etiology","bool":false},{"option":"Pathogenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Morphologic abnormalities","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What occurs in the first 24 hours after cellular injury?","answers":[{"option":"Ultra-structural and gross changes","bool":true},{"option":"Gross changes","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Ultra-structural changes","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which mechanism is not an example of apoptosis in a pathological condition?","answers":[{"option":"Viral infections","bool":false},{"option":"Pre-programmed death of cells during embryogenesis","bool":true},{"option":"Accumulation of misfolded proteins","bool":false},{"option":"DNA damage","bool":false},{"option":"Formation of apoptotic bodies","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of these forms the brush border?","answers":[{"option":"Pili","bool":false},{"option":"Microvilli","bool":true},{"option":"Stereocilia","bool":false},{"option":"Cilia","bool":false},{"option":"Fimbriae","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Apoptosis results from the activation of which cysteine proteases?","answers":[{"option":"Ligase","bool":false},{"option":"Caspases","bool":true},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Pepsin","bool":false},{"option":"Amylase","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of the following statements best describes bioavailability?","answers":[{"option":"The speed at which the administered drug reaches the systemic circulation","bool":false},{"option":"The frequency at which the administered drug reaches the systemic circulation","bool":false},{"option":"The amount of administered drug that reaches the systemic circulation","bool":false},{"option":"The rate of absorption of the administered drug into the systemic circulation","bool":false},{"option":"The fraction of administered drug that reaches the systemic circulation in unchanged form","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"A person with diabetes mellitus will have his renal epithelium injured by the accumulation of which substance?","answers":[{"option":"Melanin","bool":false},{"option":"Water","bool":false},{"option":"Lipofuscin","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen","bool":true},{"option":"Hemosiderin","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Fat is stored in the body in what form?","answers":[{"option":"Triglycerides","bool":true},{"option":"Wax","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Ghee","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which of the following is an aliphatic compound with only a carboxylic acid group?","answers":[{"option":"Fatty acid","bool":true},{"option":"Amino acid","bool":false},{"option":"Aspartic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Glucuronic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Phenol","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What are the hair-like structures present in the epididymis made of?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudopods","bool":false},{"option":"Stereocilia","bool":true},{"option":"Cilia","bool":false},{"option":"Hair","bool":false},{"option":"Microvilli","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What do the characteristics of amino acids mainly depend on?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrogen group","bool":false},{"option":"Carboxylic group","bool":false},{"option":"Amino group","bool":false},{"option":"Side chain","bool":true},{"option":"Central carbon","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What is the color of starch in a positive iodine test?","answers":[{"option":"Yellow","bool":false},{"option":"Black","bool":true},{"option":"Purple","bool":false},{"option":"Red","bool":false},{"option":"Colourless","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Peroxisomes contain which enzyme?","answers":[{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Amylase","bool":false},{"option":"Oxidase","bool":true},{"option":"Hydrolase","bool":false},{"option":"Reductase","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which property do weak acids possess?","answers":[{"option":"High pKa","bool":true},{"option":"Low pKa","bool":false},{"option":"Negative pKa","bool":false},{"option":"Very low pH","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"What is the immune-mediated response activated in a patient in response to a certain drug called?","answers":[{"option":"Tachyphylaxis","bool":false},{"option":"Anaphylaxis","bool":false},{"option":"Idiosyncrasy","bool":true},{"option":"Tolerance","bool":false},{"option":"Supersensitivity","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"In sialidosis, which of these enzymes is absent?","answers":[{"option":"Amylase","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha N-acetyl neuraminidase","bool":true},{"option":"HMG-CoA synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-galactosidase","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"The subcutaneous route is used due to which of the following advantages?","answers":[{"option":"Immediate action","bool":false},{"option":"Avoids usage of injections","bool":false},{"option":"Prevention of shock","bool":false},{"option":"Slow absorption","bool":true},{"option":"Fast absorption","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Which amino acid can disrupt helical structure?","answers":[{"option":"Valine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":false},{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Proline","bool":true},{"option":"Alanine","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"To be able to see the size, shape, and structure of a chromosome clearly, during which stage should it be observed?","answers":[{"option":"Interphase","bool":false},{"option":"Prophase","bool":false},{"option":"Anaphase","bool":false},{"option":"Telophase","bool":false},{"option":"Metaphase","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2017","question":"Anything that might be taken into the nose accidentally goes into the pharynx through what structure?","answers":[{"option":"Conchae","bool":false},{"option":"Nasopharynx","bool":true},{"option":"Meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal vestibules","bool":false}]}]
export default arr